Guide to the William Saroyan Papers, 1926-1981
Department of Special Collections
- Correspondence, ca. 1926-1981, Series 1
  - Y primary, 1.48
    - Young Rubicam, Inc.,1946-51, 4 items to WS (Box 119, Folder 11)
    - Yugoslav Films/Avala Film,.1958, 5 items to WS (Box 119, Folder 12)
  - Z miscellany, 1.49
    - Zachreson - Zeytoonian (Box 119, Folder 13)
    - Zierth - Zwart (Box 119, Folder 14)
  - Z primary, 1.50
    - Zang, Friedman Damir
    - Zaiks,1959-79, 37 items: 8 from WS (Box 119, Folder 15)
    - Darryl F. Zanuck Productions,1959-63, 51 items: 23 from WS (Box 119, Folder 16)
    - Zeitlin, Jake,n.d., 1 item to WS (Box 119, Folder 17)
    - Zelenko, Herbert,1957, 1 item to WS (Box 119, Folder 18)
    - Zolotow, Maurice,1954, 3 items: 1 from WS (Box 119, Folder 19)
  - Unidentified Correspondents, 1.51
    - Unidentified Correspondents1931; 1934-38, 35 items to WS (Box 120, Folder 1)
    - Unidentified Correspondents1939, 36 items to WS (Box 120, Folder 2)
    - Unidentified Correspondents1940-49, 14 items: 7 from WS (Box 120, Folder 3)
    - Unidentified Correspondents1951-60, 41 items: 10 from WS (Box 120, Folder 4)
    - Unidentified Correspondents1961-69, 29 items: 10 from WS (Box 120, Folder 5)
    - Unidentified Correspondents1970-81, 19 items: 4 from WS (Box 120, Folder 6)
    - Unidentified Correspondentsn.d., 41 items to WS (Box 120, Folder 7)
  - Foreign Language correspondence, 1.52
    - Armenian (and Russian),1930s (Box 121, Folder 1)
    - Armenian,1950s (Box 121, Folder 2)
    - Armenian,1960s (Box 121, Folder 3)
    - Armenian,1970s (Box 121, Folder 4)
    - Armenian,1980-81 (Box 121, Folder 5)
    - Armenian,undated (Box 121, Folder 6)
    - Armenian, Russian, notes,undated (Box 121, Folder 7)
    - French (Box 121, Folder 8)
    - German (Box 121, Folder 9)
    - Italian (Box 121, Folder 10)
- Fan mail, 1931-1981., Series 2
  This series includes all fan mail and autograph requests received by Saroyan. In some cases Saroyan replied to fan letters (though seldom to autograph requests) and his replies are included here. Also included are Christmas and birthday cards, invitations and get-well cards. In some specific cases, such as those of family members, these items have been filed with the correspondence from that individual or organization and are part of Series I.
  - Fan letters, 2.01
    - Fan letters, 1931 -1934 April (Carton 1, Folder 1)
    - Fan letters, 1934 May -Sept. (Carton 1, Folder 2)
    - Fan letters, 1934 Oct. -Nov. (Carton 1, Folder 3)
    - Fan letters, 1934 Dec. -1935 Jan. (Carton 1, Folder 4)
    - Fan letters, 1935 Feb. -April (Carton 1, Folder 5)
    - Fan letters, 1935 May -1936 March (Carton 1, Folder 6)
    - Fan letters, 1936 April -Dec. (Carton 1, Folder 7)
    - Fan letters, 1937 -1939 April (Carton 1, Folder 8)
    - Fan letters, 1939 May -Oct. (Carton 1, Folder 9)
    - Fan letters, 1939 Nov. -1942 (Carton 1, Folder 10)
    - Fan letters, 1943 -1946 June (Carton 1, Folder 11)
    - Fan letters, 1946 July -Dec. (Carton 1, Folder 12)
    - Fan letters, 1947 -1949 (Carton 1, Folder 13)
    - Fan letters, 1950 -1951 June (Carton 1, Folder 14)
    - Fan letters, 1951 July -1952 Feb. (Carton 1, Folder 15)
    - Fan letters, 1952 March -Sept. (Carton 1, Folder 16)
    - Fan letters, 1952 Oct. -1953 Jan. (Carton 1, Folder 17)
    - Fan letters, 1953 Feb. -Aug. (Carton 1, Folder 18)
    - Fan letters, 1953 Sept. -1954 April (Carton 1, Folder 19)
    - Fan letters, 1954 May -Sept. (Carton 1, Folder 20)
    - Fan letters, 1954 Oct. -1955 Jan. (Carton 1, Folder 21)
    - Fan letters, 1955 Feb. -June (Carton 1, Folder 22)
    - Fan letters, 1955 July -Dec. (Carton 1, Folder 23)
    - Fan letters, 1956 (Carton 2, Folder 12)
    - Fan letters, 1957 (Carton 2, Folder 34)
    - Fan letters, 1958 (Carton 2, Folder 58)
    - Fan letters, 1959 (Carton 2, Folder 910)
    - Fan letters, 1960 (Carton 2, Folder 1112)
    - Fan letters, 1961 (Carton 2, Folder 1315)
    - Fan letters, 1962 (Carton 2, Folder 1617)
    - Fan letters, 1963 (Carton 2, Folder 1822)
    - Fan letters, 1964 (Carton 2, Folder 2326)
    - Fan letters, 1965 (Carton 2, Folder 2730)
    - Fan letters, 1966 (Carton 3, Folder 13)
    - Fan letters, 1967 (Carton 3, Folder 47)
    - Fan letters, 1968 (Carton 3, Folder 814)
    - Fan letters, 1969 (Carton 3, Folder 1518)
    - Fan letters, 1970 (Carton 3, Folder 1922)
    - Fan letters, 1971 (Carton 3, Folder 2326)
    - Fan letters, 1972 (Carton 3, Folder 2731)
    - Fan letters, 1973 (Carton 4, Folder 14)
    - Fan letters, 1974 (Carton 4, Folder 57)
    - Fan letters, 1975 (Carton 4, Folder 811)
    - Fan letters, 1976 (Carton 4, Folder 1215)
    - Fan letters, 1977 (Carton 4, Folder 1622)
    - Fan letters, 1978 (Carton 4, Folder 2327)
    - Fan letters, 1982-84 (Carton 5, Folder 15)
    - Fan letters, 1979 (Carton 5, Folder 17)
    - Fan letters, 1980 (Carton 5, Folder 812)
    - Fan letters, 1981 (Carton 5, Folder 1314)
    - Fan letters, Undated (Carton 5, Folder 1625)
    - Byrd, Esther (Carton 6, Folder 1)
    - Williamson, James Ralph (Carton 6, Folder 26)
  - Christmas cards, 2.02
    - Christmas cards, 1947-51 (Carton 6, Folder 7)
    - Christmas cards, 1952 (Carton 6, Folder 8)
    - Christmas cards, 1953 (Carton 6, Folder 9)
    - Christmas cards, 1954 (Carton 6, Folder 10)
    - Christmas cards, 1956 (Carton 6, Folder 13)
    - Christmas cards, 1957 (Carton 6, Folder 14)
    - Christmas cards, 1959 (Carton 6, Folder 17)
    - Christmas cards, 1955 (Carton 6, Folder 1112)
    - Christmas cards, 1958 (Carton 6, Folder 1516)
    - Christmas cards, 1960 (Carton 7, Folder 1)
    - Christmas cards, 1961 (Carton 7, Folder 2)
    - Christmas cards, 1962-63 (Carton 7, Folder 3)
    - Christmas cards, 1964-69 (Carton 7, Folder 4)
    - Christmas cards, 1970 (Carton 7, Folder 5)
    - Christmas cards, 1971 (Carton 7, Folder 6)
    - Christmas cards, 1972-73 (Carton 7, Folder 7)
    - Christmas cards, 1974 (Carton 7, Folder 8)
    - Christmas cards, 1975 (Carton 7, Folder 9)
    - Christmas cards, 1976 (Carton 7, Folder 10)
    - Christmas cards, 1977 (Carton 7, Folder 11)
    - Christmas cards, 1978 (Carton 7, Folder 12)
    - Christmas cards, 1979 (Carton 7, Folder 13)
    - Christmas cards, 1980-81 (Carton 7, Folder 14)
    - Christmas cards, Undated (Carton 7, Folder 1517)
  - Birthday cards, 2.03
    - 1951-60 (Carton 8, Folder 1)
    - 1964-73 (Carton 8, Folder 2)
    - 1974-81 (Carton 8, Folder 3)
    - undated (Carton 8, Folder 4)
  - Get well cards, 2.04
    - Get well cards, 1981; n.d. (Carton 8, Folder 5)
    - 1939-56 (Carton 8, Folder 6)
    - 1957-64 (Carton 8, Folder 7)
    - 1965-71 (Carton 8, Folder 8)
    - 1972-76 (Carton 8, Folder 9)
    - 1977-81 (Carton 8, Folder 10)
    - Undated (Carton 8, Folder 11)
- Financial and Legal Papers, n.d., Series 3
  This series contains documents such as tax forms, bank statements, miscellaneous bills and receipts, wills, and real estate papers. It is by no means a complete record and researchers are urged to also consult correspondence with relevant organizations, lawyers and family members--in particular Henry Saroyan, Cosette Saroyan, and, regarding Saroyan's Malibu and Bolinas properties, Hank Saroyan and Aram Saroyan.
  - Banks, 3.01
    - American Trust Company (Carton 9, Folder 1)
    - Bank of America (Carton 9, Folder 2)
    - Bank of America (Carton 9, Folder 3)
    - Bank of Fresno (Carton 9, Folder 4)
    - Bank of Tokyo (Carton 9, Folder 5)
    - Banque Jordaan (Carton 9, Folder 6)
    - Barclays Bank Ltd. (Carton 9, Folder 7)
    - Beverly Hills National Bank Trust (Carton 9, Folder 8)
    - Beverly Hills National Bank Trust (Carton 9, Folder 9)
    - California Bank (Carton 9, Folder 10)
    - California Canadian Bank (Carton 9, Folder 11)
    - California Canadian Bank (Carton 9, Folder 12)
    - California Canadian Bank (Carton 9, Folder 13)
    - California First Bank (Carton 9, Folder 14)
    - Canadian Imperial Bank of California (Carton 9, Folder 15)
    - Central Hanover Bank Trust Co. (Carton 9, Folder 16)
    - Corn Exchange Bank Trust Co. (Carton 10, Folder 1)
    - Corn Exchange Bank Trust Co. (Carton 10, Folder 2)
    - Corn Exchange Bank Trust Co. (Carton 10, Folder 3)
    - First National City Bank of New York (Carton 10, Folder 4)
    - Guaranty Trust Co. of New York (Carton 10, Folder 5)
    - Hibernia Bank (Carton 10, Folder 6)
    - Lloyds Bank of California (Carton 10, Folder 7)
    - Santa Monica Bank (Carton 10, Folder 8)
    - Security First National of L.A. (Carton 10, Folder 9)
    - Security First National of L.A. (Carton 10, Folder 10)
    - Security First National of L.A. (Carton 10, Folder 11)
    - Swiss Credit Bank (Carton 10, Folder 12)
    - United California Bank (Carton 10, Folder 13)
    - Misc. banks (Carton 10, Folder 14)
  - Stocks, 3.02
    - Stocks, 1965 (Carton 10, Folder 15)
    - Stocks, 1966 (Carton 10, Folder 16)
    - Stocks, 1967 (Carton 10, Folder 17)
    - Stocks, 1969 (Carton 10, Folder 18)
    - Stocks, 1972-81 (Carton 10, Folder 19)
  - Bills and receipts, 3.03
    - Bills and receipts, 1936 (Carton 11, Folder 1)
    - Bills and receipts, 1939 (Carton 11, Folder 2)
    - Bills and receipts, 1941 (Carton 11, Folder 3)
    - Bills and receipts, 1942 (Carton 11, Folder 4)
    - Bills and receipts, 1943 (Carton 11, Folder 5)
    - Bills and receipts, 1943 (Carton 11, Folder 6)
    - Bills and receipts, 1945 (Carton 11, Folder 7)
    - Bills and receipts, 1946 (Carton 11, Folder 8)
    - Bills and receipts, 1947 (Carton 11, Folder 9)
    - Bills and receipts, 1949 (Carton 11, Folder 10)
    - Bills and receipts, 1950 (Carton 11, Folder 11)
    - Bills and receipts, 1951 (Carton 11, Folder 12)
    - Bills and receipts, 1951-52(Stern) (Carton 11, Folder 13)
    - Bills and receipts, 1952 (Carton 11, Folder 14)
    - Bills and receipts, 1953 (Carton 11, Folder 15)
    - Bills and receipts, 1954 (Carton 11, Folder 16)
    - Bills and receipts, 1955 (Carton 11, Folder 17)
    - Bills and receipts, 1956 (Carton 11, Folder 18)
    - Bills and receipts, 1957 (Carton 11, Folder 19)
    - Bills and receipts, 1958 (Carton 11, Folder 20)
    - Bills and receipts, 1959 (Carton 11, Folder 21)
    - Bills and receipts, 1960 (Carton 12, Folder 1)
    - Bills and receipts, 1961 (Carton 12, Folder 2)
    - Bills and receipts, 1962 (Carton 12, Folder 3)
    - Bills and receipts, 1963 (Carton 12, Folder 4)
    - Bills and receipts, 1964 (Carton 12, Folder 5)
    - Bills and receipts, 1965 (Carton 12, Folder 6)
    - Bills and receipts, 1966 (Carton 12, Folder 7)
    - Bills and receipts, 1967 (Carton 12, Folder 8)
    - Bills and receipts, 1968 (Carton 12, Folder 9)
    - Bills and receipts, 1969 (Carton 12, Folder 10)
    - Bills and receipts, 1970 (Carton 12, Folder 11)
    - Bills and receipts, 1971 (Carton 12, Folder 12)
    - Bills and receipts, 1972 (Carton 12, Folder 13)
    - Bills and receipts, 1973 (Carton 12, Folder 14)
    - Bills and receipts, 1974 (Carton 12, Folder 15)
    - Bills and receipts, 1975 (Carton 12, Folder 16)
    - Bills and receipts, 1976 (Carton 12, Folder 17)
    - Bills and receipts, 1977 (Carton 12, Folder 18)
    - Bills and receipts, 1978 (Carton 12, Folder 19)
    - Bills and receipts, 1979 (Carton 12, Folder 20)
    - Bills and receipts, 1980 (Carton 12, Folder 21)
    - Bills and receipts, n.d. (Carton 12, Folder 22)
    - Financial notebooks (Carton 12, Folder 23)
    - Financial notebooks (Carton 12, Folder 24)
  - Real Estate, 3.04
    - Real Estate records, 1940 - 1949 (Carton 13, Folder 1)
    - Real Estate records, 1950 - 1959 (Carton 13, Folder 2)
    - Real Estate records, 1960 - 1969 (Carton 13, Folder 3)
    - Real Estate records, 1970 - 1979 (Carton 13, Folder 4)
    - Real Estate records, 1980 (Carton 13, Folder 5)
  - Taxes, 3.05
    - Tax files, 1936 (Carton 13, Folder 6)
    - Tax files, 1941 (Carton 13, Folder 7)
    - Tax files, 1942 (Carton 13, Folder 8)
    - Tax files, 1943 (Carton 13, Folder 9)
    - Tax files, 1944 (Carton 13, Folder 10)
    - Tax files, 1945 (Carton 13, Folder 11)
    - Tax files, 1946 (Carton 13, Folder 12)
    - Tax files, 1947 (Carton 13, Folder 13)
    - Tax files, 1948 (Carton 13, Folder 14)
    - Tax files, 1949 (Carton 13, Folder 15)
    - Tax files, 1950 (Carton 13, Folder 16)
    - Tax files, 1951 (Carton 13, Folder 17)
    - Tax files, 1952 (Carton 13, Folder 18)
    - Tax files, 1953 (Carton 13, Folder 19)
    - Tax files, 1954 (Carton 13, Folder 20)
    - Tax files, 1959 (Carton 13, Folder 21)
    - Tax files, 1961 (Carton 13, Folder 22)
    - Tax files, 1965 (Carton 13, Folder 23)
    - Tax files, 1965 (Carton 13, Folder 24)
    - Tax files, 1968 (Carton 13, Folder 25)
    - Tax files, 1969 (Carton 13, Folder 26)
    - Tax files, 1971 (Carton 13, Folder 27)
    - Tax files, 1972 (Carton 13, Folder 28)
    - Tax files, 1973 (Carton 13, Folder 29)
    - Tax files, 1974 (Carton 13, Folder 30)
    - Tax files, 1975 (Carton 13, Folder 31)
    - Tax files, 1977 (Carton 13, Folder 32)
    - Tax files, 1978 (Carton 13, Folder 33)
    - Tax files, 1979 (Carton 13, Folder 34)
  - Wills, 3.06
    - Wills, 1951-1969 (Carton 13, Folder 35)
    - Wills, 1972-1980 (Carton 13, Folder 36)
  - Medical documents, 3.07
    - Medical documents, 1954 (Carton 13, Folder 37)
    - Medical documents, 1969 (Carton 13, Folder 38)
    - Medical documents, 1970-71 (Carton 13, Folder 39)
    - Medical documents, 1975 (Carton 13, Folder 40)
    - Medical documents, 1976 (Carton 13, Folder 41)
    - Medical documents, 1979 (Carton 13, Folder 42)
    - Medical documents, 1980-81 (Carton 13, Folder 43)
- Journals, 1934-1981, Series 4
  Journals for the years 1934-1938 contain only scattered entries, but for the remainder of the years until 1981 there are entries for all but perhaps a dozen months. In addition to regular journals, Saroyan also kept desk and pocket diaries as well as notebooks with miscellaneous entries. Correspondence and photographs found loose in all of the above items have been removed, with notations made regarding their removal. In some cases manuscripts have been bound into journals and their titles have been listed in the index to manuscripts. Saroyan occasionally gave titles to his journals and considered them to be literary pieces. Researchers are advised to consult the manuscripts, particularly the essay and personal narrative sections, for works which fill the chronological gaps in the journals.
  - Journal, 1934-38 (Carton 14, Folder 1)
    Misc. entries, notes
  - Journal, 1937 July 27 - Sept. 2 (Carton 14, Folder 2)
  - Journal, 1937 Sept. 6 (Carton 14, Folder 3)
  - Journal, 1938 Aug. 7-31 (Carton 14, Folder 4)
  - Journal, 1938 Sept. 1 - Oct. 30 (Carton 14, Folder 5)
  - Journal, 1941 (Carton 14, Folder 6)
    Notebook: Spring
  - Journal, 1941 Aug. 18-31 (Carton 14, Folder 7)
  - Journal, 1941 Aug. 21 - Sept. 1 (Carton 14, Folder 8)
  - Journal, 1941 Sept. 1-30 (Carton 14, Folder 9)
  - Journal, 1941 Oct. 1-31 (Carton 14, Folder 10)
  - Journal, 1941 Nov. 1-30 (Carton 14, Folder 11)
  - Journal, 1941 Dec. 1-31 (Carton 14, Folder 12)
  - Journal, 1942 Jan. 1 - Feb. 1 (Carton 14, Folder 13)
  - Journal, 1942 Feb. 1 - March 1 (Carton 14, Folder 14)
  - Journal, 1942 March 1-31 (Carton 14, Folder 15)
  - Journal, 1942 April 1 - May 1 (Carton 14, Folder 16)
  - Journal, 1942 May 1-18 (Carton 14, Folder 17)
    includes "What's Wrong with William?" and "Oh to be a Writer Again"
  - Journal, 1942 May 18-31 (Carton 14, Folder 18)
  - Journal, 1942 June 1-18 (Carton 14, Folder 19)
  - Journal, 1942 June 18-30 (Carton 14, Folder 20)
  - Journal, 1942 July 1-31 (Carton 14, Folder 21)
  - Journal, 1942 Aug. 1-31 (Carton 14, Folder 22)
  - Journal, 1942 Sept. 1-30 (Carton 14, Folder 23)
  - Journal, 1942 Oct. 1-11 (Carton 14, Folder 24)
    includes Dedication to "The Human Comedy"
  - Journal, 1942 Oct. 11-29 (Carton 14, Folder 25)
  - Journal, 1942 Oct. 30 - Nov. 22 (Carton 14, Folder 26)
  - Journal, 1942 Nov. 23 - Dec. 6 (Carton 14, Folder 27)
  - Journal, 1942 Dec. 7-13 (Carton 14, Folder 28)
  - Journal, 1942 Dec. 14-16 (Carton 14, Folder 29)
  - Journal, 1942 Dec. 17 - 1943 Jan. 1 (Carton 14, Folder 30)
  - Journal, 1943 Jan. 1-31 (Carton 14, Folder 31)
  - Journal, 1943 Feb. 1-12 (Carton 14, Folder 32)
    Includes "The Turk Who Might Have Lived," and "To Load a Boxcar - Summing Up"
  - Journal, 1943 Feb. 12-28 (Carton 14, Folder 33)
  - Journal, 1943 March 1-14 (Carton 15, Folder 1)
    Includes "Physical Training for Aviation Cadets"
  - Journal, 1943 March 15-18 (Carton 15, Folder 2)
  - Journal, 1943 March 19-30 (Carton 15, Folder 3)
    Includes "The Second Day"
  - Journal, 1943 March 31 - April 7 (Carton 15, Folder 4)
  - Journal, 1943 April 8-18 (Carton 15, Folder 5)
    Includes "Letter to a Dead Russian Soldier"
  - Journal, 1943 April 18-30 (Carton 15, Folder 6)
    Includes "A Note on War and Peace and the Human Race" and "You Must Take it with You"
  - Journal, 1943 April and May "extra" (Carton 15, Folder 7)
    Includes "The Merry Mad Month of May" and "The April Fool"
  - Journal, 1943 May 1-15 (Carton 15, Folder 8)
  - Journal, 1943 May 16-31 (Carton 15, Folder 9)
    Includes "The Sweetheart of Company D"
  - Journal, 1943 June 1-15 (Carton 15, Folder 10)
    Includes "The Killer" and "...And All Like That There"
  - Journal, 1943 June 16-25 (Carton 15, Folder 11)
    Includes "The Joke of Kings County" and introduction to "The Trouble with Tigers"
  - Journal, 1943 June 25-30 (Carton 15, Folder 12)
    Includes "Boredom in the Army"
  - Journal, 1943 July 1-15 (Carton 15, Folder 13)
    Includes "In Spite of Hell, A Merry Christmas to You, America"
  - Journal, 1943 July 16-25 (Carton 15, Folder 14)
  - Journal, 1943 July 26-31 (Carton 15, Folder 15)
  - Journal, 1943 Aug. 1-7 (Carton 15, Folder 16)
    Includes "Company A" and "War and Writing"
  - Journal, 1943 Aug. 8-14 (Carton 15, Folder 17)
  - Journal, 1943 Aug. 15-21 (Carton 15, Folder 18)
  - Journal, 1943 Aug. 22-31 (Carton 15, Folder 19)
  - Journal, 1943 Sept. 1-11 (Carton 15, Folder 20)
    Includes "Railroads," "Shag Mugger's Drive," "Bepo's Father, Bepo's Son," "Ohan's Boy"
  - Journal, 1943 Sept. 11-18 (Carton 15, Folder 21)
  - Journal, 1943 Sept. 18-25 (Carton 15, Folder 22)
  - Journal, 1943 Sept. 26-30 (Carton 15, Folder 23)
  - Journal, 1943 Oct. 1-9 (Carton 15, Folder 24)
  - Journal, 1943 Oct. 10-16 (Carton 15, Folder 25)
  - Journal, 1943 Oct. 17-23 (Carton 15, Folder 26)
  - Journal, 1943 Oct. 10-16 (Carton 15, Folder 27)
  - Journal, 1943 Nov. 1-15 (Carton 15, Folder 28)
  - Journal, 1943 Nov. 15-30 (Carton 15, Folder 29)
  - Journal, 1943 Dec. 1-15 (Carton 16, Folder 1)
  - Journal, 1943 Dec. 16-31 (Carton 16, Folder 2)
    Includes "I Predict for 1943" and "The Man with the Low Threshold"
  - Journal, 1944 Jan. 1-15 (Carton 16, Folder 3)
    Includes "The Adventures of a Private" and "How to Put on an Army Show"
  - Journal, 1944 Jan. 16-25 (Carton 16, Folder 4)
  - Journal, 1944 May 23 - July 30 (Carton 16, Folder 5)
    Includes "The Celebrated Bank Holiday of 1944"
  - Journal, 1944 Aug. 1-8 (Carton 16, Folder 6)
  - Journal, 1944 Aug. 8-18 (Carton 16, Folder 7)
  - Journal, 1944 Aug. 19-31 (Carton 16, Folder 8)
  - Journal, 1944 Sept. 1-10 (Carton 16, Folder 9)
  - Journal, 1944 Sept. 11-30 (Carton 16, Folder 10)
  - Journal, 1944 Oct. 1-31; "What to Do with Granny" and "Ha Ha Ha Hurrah for War" (Carton 16, Folder 11)
  - Journal, 1944 Nov. 1-30 (Carton 16, Folder 12)
  - Journal, 1944 Dec. 1-31; "Early Thursday" (Carton 16, Folder 13)
  - Notebook, 1945 (Carton 16, Folder 14)
  - Journal, 1945 Jan. 1-9 (Carton 16, Folder 15)
  - Journal, 1945 April - June (Carton 16, Folder 16)
    Includes "Joe's Old Clothes"
  - Journal, 1945 July 1-31 (Carton 16, Folder 17)
    Includes "The Adventures of Wesley Jackson"
  - Journal, 1945 Aug. 1-31 (Carton 16, Folder 18)
  - Journal, 1945 Sept. - Oct. (Carton 16, Folder 19)
  - Journal, 1945 Nov. 1-30 (Carton 16, Folder 20)
  - Journal, 1945 Dec. 1-31 (Carton 16, Folder 21)
  - Notebooks, 1946 (Carton 16, Folder 22)
  - Notebooks, 1946 (Carton 16, Folder 23)
  - Notebook, 1946 (Carton 16, Folder 24)
  - Journal, 1946 Jan. 1-31 (Carton 16, Folder 25)
  - Journal, 1946 Feb. 1-28 (Carton 16, Folder 26)
  - Journal, 1946 March 1-31 (Carton 16, Folder 27)
  - Journal, 1946 April - May (Carton 16, Folder 28)
  - Journal, 1946 June 1-30 (Carton 16, Folder 29)
  - Journal, 1946 July 1 - Aug. 8 (Carton 16, Folder 30)
  - Journal, 1946 Aug. 9 - Sept. 25 (Carton 16, Folder 31)
  - Journal, 1946 Oct. - Dec. (Carton 16, Folder 32)
  - Notebooks, 1947 (Carton 16, Folder 33)
  - Notebooks, 1947 (Carton 16, Folder 34)
  - Notebook, 1947 (Carton 16, Folder 35)
  - Journal, 1947 Jan. - March (Carton 17, Folder 1)
  - Journal, 1947 May 12 - Nov. 9 (Carton 17, Folder 2)
  - Journal, 1947 Oct. 13-30 (Carton 17, Folder 3)
    Includes "My Life, I Believe," "Child's Play," and "The Man Who Talked to Harry"
  - Journal, 1947 Oct. 31 - Nov. 20 (Carton 17, Folder 4)
  - Journal, 1947 Nov. 22 - Dec. 30 (Carton 17, Folder 5)
  - Notebook, 1948 (Carton 17, Folder 6)
  - Journal, 1948 Jan. 1 - April 14 (Carton 17, Folder 7)
    Includes "Who's Kidding Who?"
  - Journal, 1948 April 20 - June 28 (Carton 17, Folder 8)
  - Journal, 1948 June 28 - July 12 (Carton 17, Folder 9)
  - Journal, 1948 July 19 - Nov. 1 (Carton 17, Folder 10)
    Includes "Problems of the Playwright," and "Confessions of a Playwright"
  - Desk Diary, 1949 (Carton 17, Folder 11)
  - Notebook, 1949 Jan. 8-23 (Carton 17, Folder 12)
  - Notebook, 1949 Jan. 23 - Feb. 7 (Carton 17, Folder 13)
  - Notebook, 1949 Feb. (Carton 17, Folder 14)
  - Notebook, 1949 March (Carton 17, Folder 15)
  - Notebook, 1949 April 6 - May 14 (Carton 17, Folder 16)
  - Notebook, 1949 May 16 - June 10 (Carton 17, Folder 17)
  - Notebook, 1949 June 11-30 (Carton 17, Folder 18)
  - Notebook, 1949 July (Carton 17, Folder 19)
  - Notebook, 1949 July (Carton 17, Folder 20)
  - Journal, 1949 June 4 - Aug. 31 (Carton 17, Folder 21)
  - Journal, 1949 Sept. 1-30 (Carton 17, Folder 22)
    Includes "The Pacific" and "The Propagandists"
  - Journal, 1949 Sept. 30 - Dec. 16 (Carton 17, Folder 23)
    Includes "The Vegas Visit"
  - Desk Diary, 1950 (Carton 17, Folder 24)
  - Notebook, 1950 May 7 - June 18 (Carton 17, Folder 25)
  - Notebook, 1950 (Carton 17, Folder 26)
  - Journal, 1950 Jan. 1-31 (Carton 17, Folder 27)
  - Journal, 1950 Feb. 1-17 (Carton 17, Folder 28)
  - Journal, 1950 Feb. 18 - March 13 (Carton 17, Folder 29)
  - Journal, 1950 March 14-27 (Carton 17, Folder 30)
  - Journal, 1950 March 27 - April 21 (Carton 17, Folder 31)
  - Journal, 1950 April 29 - May 12 (Carton 17, Folder 32)
  - Journal, 1950 May 13 - June 7 (Carton 17, Folder 33)
  - Journal, 1950 June 16-18 (Carton 18, Folder 1)
  - Journal, 1950 June 19-25 (Carton 18, Folder 2)
  - Journal, 1950 June 26-30 (Carton 18, Folder 3)
  - Journal, 1950 July 2-31 (Carton 18, Folder 4)
  - Journal, 1950 July 31 - Aug. 10 (Carton 18, Folder 5)
  - Journal, 1950 Aug. 11-21 (Carton 18, Folder 6)
  - Journal, 1950 Aug. 22-31 (Carton 18, Folder 7)
  - Journal, 1950 Sept. 10-14 (Carton 18, Folder 8)
  - Journal, 1950 Oct. 8-15 (Carton 18, Folder 9)
  - Journal, 1950 Oct. 22 - Nov. 5 (Carton 18, Folder 10)
  - Journal, 1950 Nov. 6-11 (Carton 18, Folder 11)
  - Journal, 1950 Nov. 12-18 (Carton 18, Folder 12)
  - Journal, 1950 Nov. 19-26 (Carton 18, Folder 13)
  - Journal, 1950 Nov. 26 - Dec. 3 (Carton 18, Folder 14)
  - Journal, 1950 Dec. 3-9 (Carton 18, Folder 15)
  - Journal, 1950 Dec. 10-17 (Carton 18, Folder 16)
  - Journal, 1950 Dec. 18-26 (Carton 18, Folder 17)
  - Journal, 1950 Dec. 26 - 1951 Feb. 25 (Carton 18, Folder 18)
  - Desk Diary, 1951 (Carton 18, Folder 19)
  - Desk Diary, 1951 (Carton 18, Folder 20)
  - Journal, 1951 Feb. 3, March 26 - April 28 (Carton 18, Folder 21)